let's have the solution for our pshare
versus GX share quiz the question is for
all of the branches in this code how
much history do we need to make them all
very well predicted we have one two
three branches this Branch here is
easily predictable even without any
history so for this one any history will
work the exit Branch we do a thousand
iteration each time it's not taken
except the last time so for this Branch
again we don't need much history even
with no history using just a two bit
counter we would predict this Branch
accurately a thousand times followed by
one misprediction so it's a very good
prediction rate still this Branch
however requires some history this is
the even odd Branch so we really need to
know whether the previous outcome was
even or odd so that we can do the
opposite for pshare the even odd
handling can be done with just a history
length of one and the history length of
one will work well for these two as well
so we just need a history length of one
for gshare when we're doing this Branch
we want its previous outcome to be part
of the global history if we look at what
the global history looks like this
branch is not taken so the global
history will be zero this branch in the
very first iteration because I is 1,000
that's divisible by two is taken because
the number is even this branch is then
taken then we have this Branch zero now
it's going to be not taken
here followed by a taken here and this
pattern will repeat so really we need
this to be part of the history when
we're predicting this we need this to be
part of the history and we're predicting
this and so on in order to do that we
need the history to contain at least
this much which is three bits and
similarly here we need this to be our
history so it catches this bit not that
really there are only two possible
histories for this Branch one is the 1 1
0 and the other is 0 1 0 because the
other two branches are just having the
same outcome every time so we need a
three bit history as you can see gshare
can do a similar job to pshare except
that it needs a longer history even for
branches that are actually kind of self
determining note that gshare can also do
those correlative branches that pshare
cannot do